Finding Aid for the A. Conger Goodyear Papers, 1683-1964 (bulk 1885-1964)
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
A. Conger Goodyear Papers
1683 - 1964
1885 - 1964
Mss. C64-2
Goodyear, A. Conger (Anson Conger), 1877-1964
14.5 linear feet ( 24 boxes, 6 volumes )
Collection of Anson Conger Goodyear, a buffalo local business man, major general, and patron of the fine arts and collector; includes family correspondence, diary and scrap books, his speeches and writings, business papers, and military related correspondence.
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Access restricted until further notice, as per Melissa Brown, Museum Director, May 30, 2013.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Please see librarian for acquisition information.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
A. Conger Goodyear
Anson Conger Goodyear, businessman, military officer, postwar European relief executive and humanitarian, author, founder of the Museum of Modern Art, and collector of modern paintings, rare books and historical manuscripts, was born in Buffalo to Charles W. Goodyear (1846-1911) and Ella Conger Goodyear (1853-1940). The Goodyear family in America is traced back to Stephen Goodyear, a founder of New Haven, Conn. and deputy governor of Connecticut from 1643 to 1658.
Parents
His father, Charles W. Goodyear, studied law in Buffalo, was admitted to the bar in 1871, and joined the law firm of Cleveland, Bissel and Sicard (later, Bissell, Sicard and Goodyear after Cleveland was elected mayor of Buffalo). He was a lifelong friend of Grover Cleveland, and the Goodyear family made many visits to the White House during Cleveland's two presidential terms. At the height of his success in the legal profession, Charles W. Goodyear quit to enter the lumber and railroading business with his brother Frank H. Goodyear. They made vast gains from their business operations', which had gotten their start in Pouter County, Pennsylvania Over the years their interests expanded to include the Buffalo and Susquehanna Railroad, Great Southern Lumber Company, Buffalo Susquehanna Coal and Coke Company, Powhattan Coal Company, and other concerns. Ella Conger Goodyear had an abiding interest and talent in music. She was graduated from the Buffalo Female Academy and later studied music in Brooklyn. She traveled extensively with the quartet of St. Paul's. After a serious illness, religion became an important part of her life: in 1907 she founded a bible class, which she continued until 1934, and in 1913 she published a book, The Journey of Jesus.
Early Life
A. Conger Goodyear was educated locally at the Misses Hoffman School on Virginia Street, the School of Practice (graduating in 1892), and the new Nichols School. In 1895 he enrolled at Yale, where he was a reporter for the Yale Daily News and a member of The Wolf's Head during his senior year.
After receiving his degree, Goodyear traveled abroad for a time before returning to the United States to begin work in the family's lumber and railroading business. On June 29, 1904 he was married to Mary Forman. With the death of his uncle Frank Goodyear in 1907, he became the first vice-president of the Buffalo and Susquehanna Railroad as well as second vice-president of the Great Southern Lumber Company. In 1911 he succeeded his father as a director of the Albright Art Gallery (the Buffalo Fine Arts Academy).
World War I
As the United States inched closer to joining the Allies in World War I, Goodyear joined in the preparedness effort by attending one of the first military training camps held at Plattsburgh, N.Y. under General Leonard Wood "in the summer of 1915. For the next two years he participated in more military training exercises, marching as Grand Marshall in the Buffalo Preparedness Parade in the summer of 1916.and becoming involved in the efforts of Theodore Roosevelt and William J. Donovan to organize a Buffalo regiment. Just as the United States declared war, Goodyear was assigned to the 307th Field Artillery as a Captain. Soon, however, he was sent to the School of Fire at Fort Sill, Oklahoma, where he was retained as an instructor. From there he went on the Field Artillery Central officers Training School at Camp Zachary Taylor near Louisville, Kentucky, and then was assigned to the 81st Field Artillery Regiment. At last, Goodyear sailed to Europe, hoping to engage in battle -- but he landed at Brest on November 9, 1918, only two days before the Armistice was declared.
Goodyear stayed in Europe as an inspector of American railroad troops. In 1919 President Hoover appointed him as president of the Coal Commission of the Supreme Economic Council for territories that included the former empire of Austria, Hungary and Poland. In August of the same year he was assigned to Upper Silesia as a Commissioner of Investigation and a Chairman of the Coal Committee.
Business
In the 1920's Goodyear returned to business. As vice president of the Great Southern Lumber Company he became concerned about the depletion of forest lands, and the company began to explore methods of reforestation. Goodyear's company was one of the first to experiment in these methods on a large scale. When the Bogalusa, Ala. mill shut down, it was feared that the New Orleans Great Northern Railroad would go bankrupt; therefore A.C. Goodyear bought stock in the Gulf, Mobile and Northern Railroad and a merger took place. Goodyear also served as a director of numerous other corporations, including the Gaylord Container Corporation and Paramount Pictures.
Art Collecting
During the 1920's Goodyear became increasingly more interested in the world of art, and in collecting in particular. He made several trips to Europe to visit galleries and artists and to acquire paintings and sculpture. In 1928 he moved to New York City, where he established the Museum of Modern Art, which he directed as President during its crucial early years until 1939, when it moved into its famous modern home on West 53rd Street. Around 1939 his reputation as the foremost patron of the modern style was enhanced further when he commissioned Edward A. Stone to build him a house on a hilltop at Old Westbury, Long Island, which was the epitome of modern design (and, for a while, the object of contempt among his wealthy traditional neighbors).
World War II
When World War II broke out, Goodyear once again answered the call to arms. In 1940 he received a commission as Colonel in the New York National Guard and was assigned to organize and command the 17th Regiment. In 1943 he was promoted to Brigadier General. In 1944 and 1945 he served as a representative of the American Red Cross in the Pacific Theater (an experience which Goodyear describes in his memoir One Wide Expanse). After that assignment Goodyear was promoted to Major General in command of the New York Guard's 1st Division. In January of 1947, Secretary of War Patterson requested his services to tour occupied Germany and evaluate the morale of American troops there. Goodyear's military activities continued even past his formal retirement when he served on the board of trustees of Norwich University, a military academy in Northfield, Vermont, throughout the 1950's.
Goodyear's first marriage ended in divorce. Children from that marriage were sons George F. and Stephen G. Goodyear, and a daughter, Mrs. Theodore Kenefick. In 1950 Goodyear was married to Zaidee Bliss.
Many of A. Conger Goodyear's writings were privately printed for distribution to friends and family members. Most of them can be found either in this collection or in the BECHS library; they include the following titles: The Museum of Modern Art, the First Ten Years (1943); John George Milburn Jr.: A Memoir (1938); [Goodyear] Family History, By a Descendant (194-?); One Wide Expanse (1946); The Loq of the Yakima (1903?); and Sidelights (1960). The Spring 1961 issue of Niagara Frontier also features a sketch of his mother.
A. Conger Goodyear died on April 23, 1964.
Notes prepared by Peter Nelson.
Scope and Content Note
Papers documenting family and personal history, military service in both World Wars, and Goodyear's business and cultural interests as vice- president of the Buffalo and Susquehanna Railroad, vice-president of the Great Southern Lumber Company, a director, 1911, of the Albright Art Gallery in Buffalo, and a founder and president, 1929-1939, of the Museum of Modern Art in New York City. Includes annual reports of various railroad companies and other businesses; correspondence, unpublished articles, memoirs, speeches, diaries, scrapbooks and photo albums, and materials concerning Mr. and Mrs. Grover Cleveland, including articles, notes and letters. Correspondents include William J. Donovan, Ham Andrews, James W. Wadsworth and Herbert Hoover.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in twelve series:
I. Early Goodyear Family History
II. Writings
III. Correspondence
IV. Military Career
V. Business Interests
VI. Fine Arts Activities
VII. Manuscript and Autograph Collecting
VIII. Norwich University
IX. Degrees and Other Honors
X. Miscellaneous
XI. Grover Cleveland Papers and Notes
XII. Albums and Scrapbooks.
III arranged alphabetically by correspondent; other series arranged chronologically.
Container List
- Early Goodyear Family History, 1860-1961, I.
  - A.G. Conger: N.Y. State Legislative manual, 1863 (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Survey maps of Central New York by Stephen Thorn (ancestor of George Goodyear's great grandmother), undated (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence of C.W. Goodyear and A.C. Goodyear, 1860-1940 (Box-folder 1.3)
    Includes letters of Frances F. Cleveland Folsom
  - Charles Goodyear - diary, 1865 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - E.P. Goodyear (mother of Charles W. Goodyear) - diaries, 1885, 1888, 1890, 1892, 1897 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Report of the Buffalo and Susquehanna Railroad Company, 1895 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Letters to/from/regarding Anson Conger Goodyear at Yale College, 1896-1899; The Horoscope, May 1898 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Funeral service for William McKinley, Buffalo: program, 15 September 1901 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Elisha Walker, Concerning Iron Making, With Special Reference to the Buffalo and Susquehanna Iron Company, 1903 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Commemorative booklet on the visit of the King and Queen of the Belgians to Buffalo, 6 October 1919 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Railway and Locomotive Historical Society: Bulletin 49, May 1939; Buffalo and Susquehanna Railway and Allied Interests 1904, Booklet (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Frank H. Goodyear - memorial scrapbook, 1907 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Charles W. Goodyear - memorial scrapbook, 1911 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Ellen Conger Goodyear: The Journey of Jesus, 1928, Book; inscribed 1935 (Box-folder 2.9)
  - Correspondence concerning publication of Goodyear family history, 1939-1961 (Box-folder 2.10)
  - Ellen Conger Goodyear: ALS from Mrs. H.C. Albro, undated (Box-folder 2.11)
- Writing, 1903-circa 1960, II.
  - Miscellaneous writings and speeches of Anson Conger Goodyear, circa 1918-1945 (Box-folder 2.12)
  - Life (autobiography, with photographs) (Box-folder 3.1-3.3)
  - Travel (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Log of the Yakima, January 10th to March 1st, 1903 undated, Booklet (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Borrowed Time, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Silver Tip Ranch, 1922-1947, 1946-1952, Published booklet with correspondence (Box-folder 3.7)
  - Sidelights, [1960] (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Correspondence and photos related to Sidelights, 1960 (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Miscellaneous writings, undated (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Unpublished articles, papers and speeches, circa 1924-1944 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Far East travel diary, 1948 (Box-folder 4.5-4.6)
  - Veterans of the Vulcania, March-April 1951, Bound Volume (Box 5)
    Travel diary
  - Mediterranean travel diary, 1953 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Italian travel diary, 1953 (Box-folder 5.2-5.3)
  - Common Place Book, undated (Box-folder 5.4)
  - Common Place Book (2), undated (Box-folder 5.5)
  - John George Milburn, Jr.: A Memoir, 1938, Bound volume, privately printed (Box 6)
    Includes correspondence regarding J.G. Milburn & Memoir, 1935-1938
- Correspondence, 1912-1962, III.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Index to Arts and Letters (fragment); letters related to National Theater project, 1936-1943 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Andrews, W.G. (Ham): correspondence, 1930-1949 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - A (Box-folder 6.3)
  - B (Box-folder 6.4)
  - C (Box-folder 7.1)
  - D (Box-folder 7.2)
  - E (Box-folder 7.3)
  - F (Box-folder 7.4)
  - G (Box-folder 7.5)
  - H (Box-folder 7.6)
  - I (Box-folder 7.7)
  - J (Box-folder 7.8)
  - K, L (Box-folder 7.9)
  - M (Box-folder 8.1)
  - N (Box-folder 8.2)
  - P, Q (Box-folder 8.3)
  - R (Box-folder 8.4)
  - S (Box-folder 8.5)
  - T (Box-folder 8.6)
  - U, V (Box-folder 8.7)
  - W (Box-folder 8.8)
  - X, Y, Z (Box-folder 8.9)
- Military Career, 1915-1952, IV.
  - First Training Regiment, Plattsburgh, New York., 1915 (Box-folder 9.1)
    Includes roster and views
  - First Training Regiment, Plattsburgh, New York (Box-folder 9.2)
    Includes correspondence with Theodore Roosevelt Jr. and William Donovan regarding organizing cavalry regiment in World War I, 1916-1917
  - Records and official documents related to Anson Conger Goodyear's military career, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 9.3)
  - Military commissions, certificates and discharges, 1915-1919, 1952 (Box-folder 9.4)
  - History of the 307th Field Artillery, 1917-1919, Bound Volume, privately printed, undated (Box 9)
  - War Records of the Knickerbocker Club, 1914-1918 (), Bound Volume (Box 9)
    Privately printed for the Knickerbocker Club, New York, 1922
  - Letters of Anson Conger Goodyear to M[ary] F[orman] G[oodyear], 1919 (Box-folder 10.1-10.2)
  - Correspondence with James W. Wadsworth Jr. and others concerning presidential nomination of General Leonard Wood, 1919-1920, 1928 (Box-folder 10.3)
  - Ernst Hesterberg, Alle Mache den A.- und S.- Raeten: KamDf um Schlesien. Breslau: Wilh. Gottl. Korn, 1932, Bound Volume (Box 10)
  - Translation and correspondence concerning Ernst Hesterberg's World War I memoirs, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 10.4)
  - Herbert Hoover letters, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 10.5)
    Includes transcripts, originals, and correspondence related to publication of Anson Conger Goodyear's Tramping for Hoover, 1959
  - Clippings, rosters and other materials related to military career, 1918-1956 (Box-folder 10.6)
    Includes Paris edition of New York Herald, 12 November 1918
  - 17th Regiment, New York National Guard: book commemorating dinner in honor of Colonel Anson Conger Goodyear, 18 June 1941 (Box-folder 10.7)
  - Correspondence and photos related to travels as Red Cross liaison officer in Pacific theater, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 11.1)
  - 71st Regiment, NY National Guard: souvenir news bulletin, 18 May 1946 (Box-folder 11.2)
  - Report to the Secretary of War (trip to Germany to study morale of U.S. occupying troops), 28 April 1947 (Box-folder 11.3)
  - One Wide Expanse, Bound Volume (Box 11)
    Includes correspondence, clippings, maps, etc., 1944-1946
- Business Interests, 1906-1954, V.
  - New Orleans Great Northern Railroad Company: Annual Reports, 1906-1924, Bound Volume (Box 12)
  - Great Southern Lumber Company: Annual Reports, 1907-1923, Bound Volume (Box 12)
  - Great Southern Lumber Company: Annual Reports, 1924-1929 (Box-folder 12.1)
  - Great Southern Lumber Company: Annual Reports, 1930-1938 (Box-folder 12.2)
  - Gulf, Mobile and Northern Railroad Company: Annual Reports, 1928-1939, Bound Volume (Box 13)
  - Gulf, Mobile and Northern Railroad Company, 1940-1946, Bound Volume (Box 13)
    Includes Annual Reports
  - Paramount Pictures Inc., 1936-1946, Bound Volume (Box 13)
    Includes Annual Reports,
  - Gulf Pacific Lines and Redwood Lines, Inc., 1 October 1930, Bound Volume (Box 13)
    Includes Appraisal Report
  - Bogalusa Paper Company, Inc. and Robert Gaylord, Inc., 27 May 1937, [Bound Volume] (Box 14)
    Includes report
  - Gaylord Container Corporation, 1937-1946; includes Annual Reports, Bound Volume (Box 14)
  - Gaylord Container Corporation, 1942 includes Annual reports regarding sale of 6,000,000 Fifteen-Year 3 ½% Sinking Fund Debenture Bonds, Bound Volume (Box 14)
  - Eighth Annual Report of Swayne & Hoyt, Ltd. and Gulf Pacific Main Line, Ltd. (for the fiscal year ended ) 31 December 1938, Bound Volume (Box 14)
  - Reports, publications and other materials related to Anson Conger Goodyear business interests, 1922-1954 (Box-folder 14.1)
- Fine Arts Activities, 1923-1961, VI.
  - Souvenirs of dinner in honor of Anson Conger Goodyear in "appreciation for all that [he] has done for American art in this city during the past ten years," New York City, 13 June 1939 (Box-folder 15.1-15.3)
  - Correspondence concerning opening of Museum of Modern Art, 1939 (Box-folder 15.4)
  - Museum of Modern Art - The First Ten Years 1943, Boxed Volume (Box 15)
    Part 1: A.C. Goodyear, The Museum of Modern Art The First Ten Years (book, privately printed, 1943)
    Part 2: Correspondence, 1943
  - Art publications with articles by Anson Conger Goodyear, 1930-1944 (Box-folder 16.1)
  - Art publications with articles by Anson Conger Goodyear, 1949-1958 and undated (Box-folder 16.2)
  - Catalogs of artworks collected by Anson Conger Goodyear, 1923-1954 undated (Box-folder 16.3)
  - Auction catalog: Highly Important Impressionist and Modern Paintings and Drawings, Sotheby & Co., 25 November 1959 (Box-folder 16.4)
  - Catalog: Gifts to the Albright-Knox Art Gallery From A. Conger Goodyear, 1962-1963 1962-1963 (Box-folder 16.5)
  - Miscellaneous booklets and catalogs, 1925-1964 (Box-folder 16.6)
  - University of Buffalo, Niagara Frontier Convocation: souvenir booklet, 1951 (Box-folder 16.7)
  - Adolph Zukor, The Public Is Never Wrong: The Autobiography of Adolph Zukor (New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1953) 1953, Boxed Volume (Box 16)
  - Inventory: Gifts to the Museum of Modern Art, Bound Volume (Box 17)
  - Inventory: Gifts to the Albright Art Gallery, Bound Volume (Box 17)
  - Inventory: Works of Art Formerly Owned, Bound Volume (Box 17)
  - Inventory: Works Owned by Anson Conger Goodyear, February 1961, Bound Volume (Box 17)
- Manuscript and Autograph Collecting, 1926-1949, VII.
  - Yale Alumni Weekly, 9 April and 7 May 1926 (Box-folder 18.1)
    Include articles about manuscript collection of Anson Conger Goodyear
  - Clippings and memorandum concerning sale of Anson Conger Goodyear autograph collection, 1927 (Box-folder 18.2)
  - Auction catalog: American and English Autograph Collection of A.C. Goodyear, Anderson Galleries, Feb 1-2, 1927, Bound Volume (Box 18)
  - Yale University Library Gazette, January 1949 (Box-folder 18.3)
    Includes article about donation of Yale letters from collection of Anson Conger Goodyear
- Norwich University, 1950-1963, VIII.
  - Norwich University War Whoop (yearbook), 1953, Bound Volume (Box 18)
  - Budget report, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 18.4)
  - Chronology (concerning E.N. Harmon and Norwich), 1950-1959 (Box-folder 18.5)
  - E.N. Harmon correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 18.6)
  - E.N. Harmon correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 18.7)
  - E.N. Harmon correspondence, 1954 (Box-folder 19.1)
  - E.N. Harmon correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 19.2)
  - E.N. Harmon correspondence, 1957 (Box-folder 19.3)
  - E.N. Harmon correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 19.4)
  - E.N. Harmon correspondence, 1961 (Box-folder 19.5)
  - E.N. Harmon correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 19.6)
- Degrees and Other Honors, 1952-1962, IX.
  - Norwich University - honorary LL.D, 1952 (Box-folder 20.1)
  - University of Buffalo - Chancellor's Medal, 1955 (Box-folder 20.2)
  - Adelphi College - Honorary Doctor of Fine Arts, 1958, Bound volume (Box 20)
  - Crown Zellerbach Corporation - Resolution appointing ANSON CONGER GOODYEAR Director Emeritus, [1962?], Bound volume (Box 20)
  - Other degrees and honors, 1952-1961 (Box-folder 20.3)
- Miscellaneous, 1893-1964, X.
  - Correspondence and clippings concerning donation of papers to Buffalo History Museum, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 20.4)
    Includes obituary, 24 April 1964
  - George F. Goodyear, The Red Heap (description of a 1952 trip to the western U.S.) (Box-folder 20.5)
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 20.6)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1897-1944 (Box-folder 20.7)
  - Clipping of Nichols School football team photo, 1893 (Box-folder 20.8)
  - Printing plate of Nichols School football team photo, 1893 (Box-folder 20.9)
- Grover Cleveland Papers and Notes, 1881-1941, XI.
  - Published articles about Cleveland, 1909-1940, undated (Box-folder 20.10)
  - Notes, undated (Box-folder 20.11)
  - Index of newspaper references to Cleveland, 1881-1887 (Box-folder 20.12)
  - Photos, 1891-1892 (Box-folder 20.13)
    Includes photos of Allen house, Black Rock
  - Inaugural ball and reception commemorative placard, 4 March 1883 (Box-folder 20.14)
- Albums and Scrapbooks, 1883-1963, XII.
  Unless specified in parentheses, the contents of individual albums and scrapbooks are diverse, generally reflecting the entire range of Goodyear's activities during the span of dates indicated for each volume.
  - Goodyear family records, 1684-1910 (Box 20, Volume 1)
  - Goodyear family records (mostly concerning Anson Conger Goodyear), 1852-1930 (Box 20, Volume 2)
  - Charles W. Goodyear letters, 1884-1909 (Box 20, Volume 3)
    Most from President and Mrs. Grover Cleveland; also includes invitations and souvenirs
  - Photo album (Plattsburgh, 1915; Europe, 1917-1918) (Box 21, Volume 4)
  - Photo album (France, coal mission, Upper Silesia), 1918 (Box 21, Volume 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1918-1939 (Box 21, Volume 6)
    "all prepared under the direction of my mother"
  - Scrapbook, 1920-1943 (Box 21, Volume 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1920-1951 (Box 21, Volume 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1954 (Box 21, Volume 9)
  - Scrapbook (military - 17th Reg. NYG), 1940-1948 (Box 21, Volume 10)
  - Scrapbook (Museum of Modern Art; early photos of house at 30 Wheatley Rd., Old Westbury; New York Guard letters), 1939-1946 (Box 21, Volume 11)
  - Photo album (trip to Pacific as Red Cross liaison), 1944-1945 (Box 22, Volume 12)
  - Photo album (trip to Pacific as Red Cross liaison), 1944-1945 (Box 22, Volume 13)
  - Scrapbook, 1944-1950 (Box 23, Volume 14)
  - Photo album (Germany), 1947 (Box 23, Volume 15)
  - Scrapbook, 1950-1955 (Box 23, Volume 16)
  - Scrapbook, 1955-1960 (Box 24, Volume 17)
  - Scrapbook, 1957-1963 (Box 24, Volume 18)
  - Scrapbook, 1961 (Box 24, Volume 19)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Donovan, William J. (William Joseph), 1883-1959; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1887-1944; Wadsworth, James Wolcott, 1877-1952; Cleveland, Frances Folsom, 1864-1947; Goodyear, Ella, 1853-1940; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Andrews, W.G. (Walter Gresham), 1889-1949; Harmon, Ernest Nason, 1894-1979; New Orleans Great Northern Railroad Company; Gulf, Mobile and Northern Railroad Company; Great Southern Lumber Company; Norwich University; Gaylord Container Corporation; Buffalo & Susquehanna Railroad Company; Buffalo History Museum
Subject Terms